In one of the longest-running studies in history,
researchers found that the biggest predictor of health,
happiness and longevity amongst the participants
was strong social connections.
What this means for us is that our ability to cultivate strong relationships
plays an important role in our learning, well-being and resilience.
There are four not-so-secret secrets
to establishing strong relationships:
attention, vulnerability, empathy, and compassion.
AVEC, which means “with” in French, is an appropriate coincidence,
since interpersonal resilience is all about
how we interact with others.
With attention, we tune into other people and get curious.
Making eye contact activates our social brain,
our parasympathetic nervous system.
So we physically turn our body towards the person
and maintain eye contact.
We listen actively, ask genuine questions,
and withhold judgment.
With vulnerability, we express ourselves fully and authentically.
While it may feel like we are stepping out of our comfort zone,
sharing our thoughts and emotions and accepting responsibility,
even in the toughest situations,
has a positive impact on our relationships.
There's also power in acknowledging our fears,
or simply saying, “I don't know.”
With empathy, we try to understand and identify with the emotions
and perspectives that others bring to the situation.
We listen deeply in order to understand
what they're going through.
Empathy is the foundation for compassion.
And with compassion, we demonstrate our concern for others
and our desire to alleviate their pain.
We communicate that we genuinely want to be of service
by offering help and support.
Together, these four elements help us form
those important social connections.
Without them, we miss the opportunity to build the strong relationships
necessary to do our best individual and collective work.